

Chimezie, Emeka Great

Junior Frontend Engineer

A passionate & Unique Software Developer with 1 year of experience in developing real-life projects, with an increasing desire to learn and grow; enjoys working with new technologies. Resourceful team player with strong interpersonal and communication skill. Ability to diagnose problems and proffer solutions. Possess solid recommendations on integrity, honesty, hardwork and dynamic leadership qualities.

- Lagos, Nigeria
- @Great4Codes
- github.com/great-emeka

- +2347065910409
- in linkedin.com/in/emeka-great-chimezie-62927a175
- web.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100003667734546
- stackoverflow.com/users/12297378/great-emeka

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer(Intern) Genesys TechHub

03/2007 - Present

Genesys is centered community, focused on growing talent, sustaining businesses and developing technical capacity in Nigeria.

Responsibilities:

- Built a Todo List App with Vanila JavaScript
- Building Semantic and Responsive Web applications (Portfolio Web App)
- Implementing and turning of designs into codes with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Consuming weekly courses and completing of tasks

Frontend Developer (Intern) Esettlement Limited

05/2020 - 07/2020

Responsibilities:

- Collaborating with senior developers remotely to complete daily tasks
- Implementing and turning designs to codes
- Worked on company mobile App with Angular and Ionic

Contact: Praise Hart (Supervisor) - Praise@esettlementgroup.com

Software Developer (Intern) Mira Technologies Limited

07/2019 - 12/2019

In this company, I completed my six months of mandatory University InternshipProgramme.

Responsibilities:

- Developed robust Web applications collaboratively with Senior Devs.
- Built basic web projects for client.
- Maintained & redesigned existing Website UI for clients
- Built and hosted Wordpress websites

Contact: Ifeanyi Ifeabunike (CEO) - icisystemng@gmail.com

EDUCATION

Electrical & Electronic Engineering (B.eng) Federal University of Technology, Owerri

10/2015 - Present

Option

 Electronic & Computer Engineering

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

TODO LIST APP (04/2020 - 04/2020)

- A Mobile First Todo List App Developed for the LIPE (LOCKDOWN INTERNSHIP PROGRAM FOR ENGINEERS) that allows Users VIEW, CREATE/ADD, EDIT/UPDATE, AND DELETE their daily TODO LIST. Built with: HTML, CSS & JAVASCRIPT.
- Link: https://great-emeka.github.io/LIPE-To-do/

CORONA ESTIMATOR (03/2020 - 04/2020)

- This is an eligibility assessment that got me into the Andela 2020 #BuildforSDG program, in which Built an overly simplified COVID-19 infection impact estimator, to help combat the pandemic.
- Technologies used: JJAVASCRIPT, HTML, CSS & BOOTSRAP.
- Link: https://great-emeka.github.io/Corona Estimator/

GREAT-HUB APP (11/2019 - Present)

- A web Application with chat forums where Developers and Tech Enthusiasts from across the globe can meet, chat, learn and teach each other especially the upcoming developers.
- Link: great-emeka.github.io/greathub-app/

ACHIEVEMENTS

Expert Level in Building Websites with HTML5, CSS & JavaScript (07/2020 - Present)

This is a Pluralsight IQ Skill Assessment gotten from the Google, Pluralsight and Andela AfricanScholarship Internship programme 2020. Like: https://app.pluralsight.com/score/skill-assessment/html-css-javascript/summary?context=skills

INTERESTS

Technical writing Reading Programming

Football